

Profile

I'm a UX Designer with a software design background.

Over the past 16 years I've seen all different aspects of the development process: gathering user and business requirements, designing, developing, testing, implementing and managing complex applications. I'm a certified Scrum Master.

I'm passionate about designing and testing user-centered products - whether it's a prototype or the final result.

I am currently looking for a new opportunity where I can combine my past experience with my passion for UX design.



jopped@gmail.com



+31 6 24 15 69 59



jopped



www.linkedin.com/in/joppe.dekker

Joppe Dekker

UX Designer

Working experience

2016 – 2017 DevOps Engineer, *Vivat Verzekeringen* 2009 – 2016 Functional designer, *Vivat Verzekeringen*

As a functional designer, I am responsible for creating and maintaining functional design specifications for multiple complex back office systems. I am part of a multidisciplinary DevOps-team focused on the maintaining complex back office applications.

Main tasks:

- Gathering and prioritizing internal (business) requirements from users, product owners, and other stakeholders
- Designing user interfaces, creating user flows and writing functional and technical specifications
- Develop and execute test cases for the functional acceptance tests
- Develop test cases for and coordinating the user acceptance tests
- Implementation of the changes

Projects:

- Application management and implementation of several Robotic Process Automation solutions
- Designing and testing the mandate system (SEPA)
- Designing and testing complex batch programs that create custom files for external parties
- Designing and customizing our departments Sharepoint site
- Introduction of Scrum methodology in our team

2002 – 2009 Application manager, SNS REAAL Groep

As an application manager, I was responsible for the functional application management of several complex back office applications (CRM)

Main tasks:

- Analyzing and solving problems
- Responsible for the change management
- Reviewing user flows, wireframes and functional specifications
- Develop and execute testcases for the functional acceptance tests
- Develop testcases for and coordinating the user acceptance tests
- Implementation of the changes
- Writing manuals and release notes

Projects:

Designing and testing features for a new CRM application

Certification

UX Immersion *Careerfoundry*April 2018

UX Fundamentals CareerfoundryJuni 2017

Professional Scrum Master I Scrum.orgDecember 2014

TMAP NEXT® Test Engineer EXIN

Augustus 2014

ASL 2 EXIN

Februari 2017

Skills

- User-Centered Design
- Competitive Analysis
- Requirements engineering
- Generative and Evaluative Research
- User Personas
- Information Architecture
- User Flows
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Functional specifications
- Technical specifications
- Usability testing
- Preference testing





jopped



Education

2017-Now	Certified UX Designer, Careerfoundry An intensive training program for UX Designers, specializing in UX process and methodology, data driven approaches to strategy as well as prototyping, wireframing, and conversion rate optimization.
1997 – 2001	Bachelor's Degree Business economics, HES Amsterdam HBO-Fulltime, business economics, specializing in Logistic Management
1990 -1997	HAVO and VWO, Da Vinci-college Purmerend

Courses

2016	Communicating in an assertive and self-confident way				
2015	Exam training IREB Foundation				
2014	Business English with knowledge transfer				
2013	Business- and Information analysis				
2012	CMMI for development				
2011	Functional design specifications for administrative systems				
2010	Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt				
2006	Project management methods				
2005 – 2006	005 – 2006 Several internal courses on Application management				
	(ITIL, Testing according to TMAP, Querying with SQL)				

Knowledge and skills

Software & tools:		Database tools		Languages	
•	Optimal workshop	•	MS Access	•	Dutch
•	Balsamiq	•	MS Query / SQL	•	English
•	Sketch			•	German
•	Invision		Methods		

Scrum

Kanban

ITIL

Volunteer experience

TFS

Sharepoint

ServiceNow

2008 – now Committee member Stichting Constant van Gestel Fonds and webmaster of www.stichtingconstantvangestel.nl

1999 – 2011 Writer for the glossy magazine Aniway. Writing reviews about Japanese animation, comics and computer games.

Hobbies and interests

Meetups, movies, board games, Virtual Reality, computer games, Japanese animation, comics and manga.